Finding Aid for Solar Car Team (University of Michigan) records, 1985-2009
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Accession, 2008
  - Sponsor Files
    - Albin Business Center (Box 20)
    - Allied Signal Alloy Industries (Box 20)
    - Alro Steel, 2004 (Box 20)
    - Amerex [Spears Fire & Safety Services, Inc.], 1997-1998 (Box 20)
    - American Iron and Steel (Box 20)
    - AMP (Box 20)
    - Ana Digics, Inc. (Box 20)
    - Anderson Consulting (Box 20)
    - Ann Arbor Communications, 1998 (Box 20)
    - Ann Arbor Welding Supply, 1998 (Box 20)
    - Applied Power (Box 20)
    - Atkins & Pearce, 1994 (Box 20)
    - Axson North America, Inc., 1998 (Box 20)
    - Becker Group (Box 20)
    - Bitrode Corporation, 1998 (Box 20)
    - Bodine Electric Company (Box 20)
    - Boeing, 2001 (Box 20)
    - Boise Cascade, 1998 (Box 20)
    - Bondo, 1997 (Box 20)
    - Bouton, A.L., Co., 1997 (Box 20)
    - Breasco, 1998 (Box 20)
    - BSB Manufacturing, 1999 (Box 20)
    - Bussmann (Division of Cooper Industries), 1998 (Box 20)
    - Butki Tool & Carbide, 1997 (Box 20)
    - CAEN (Box 20)
    - Central Screw Co., 1997 (Box 20)
    - CGI, 1998 (Box 20)
    - Chet Jones Cabintery (Box 20)
    - Chrysler Corporation (Box 20)
    - Ciba Specialty Chemicals, 2000 (Box 20)
    - Clarklift of Cleve, 1999 (Box 20)
    - Coca Cola of Michigan, 1998-2000 (Box 20)
    - Colgate/Palmolive, 1998 (Box 20)
    - Collegiate China (Box 20)
    - Commodore Cargo, 2000 (Box 20)
    - Compix Inc., 1997 (Box 20)
    - Cooper Industries Foundation,1992 (Box 20)
    - Cooper Tools, 1998 (Box 20)
    - Cooper & Brass, 1997-1998 (Box 20)
    - Coppos Films, 1997-1998 (Box 20)
    - C.O. Tools, 1999 (Box 20)
    - Coxreels, 1998 (Box 20)
    - Cruising Equipment, 1999 (Box 20)
    - Custom Resins (Box 20)
    - Cytec Engineering Materials, 1994 (Box 20)
    - Dallas Miniconductor (Box 20)
    - Dana (Box 20)
    - Datron, 1998 (Box 20)
    - De-Comp Composites, 1997-1998 (Box 20)
    - Dense (Box 20)
    - Detroit Edison (Box 20)
    - De Walt (Box 20)
    - Dexter Corporation (Box 20)
    - DIAB (Box 20)
    - Digi-Key, 1997-1998 (Box 20)
    - DuPont, 1997-1999 (Box 20)
    - DuPont Automotive, 1999 (Box 20)
    - Duracell, 1992 (Box 20)
    - DuraVent, 1998 (Box 20)
    - Dynabrade (Box 20)
    - Eaton Corporation (Box 20)
    - ECD Energy Conversion Devices, 1993 (Box 20)
    - Electrical Systems Sponsors, 2000-2001 (Box 20)
    - Electro-Sensory Inc. (Box 20)
    - Elmo Manufacturing (Box 21)
    - Elmhart Helicoil (Box 21)
    - EMF -- Evaporated Metal Films Corporation (Box 21)
    - Explorer, LLC., 2000 (Box 21)
    - Fairchild Fastners, 2005 (Box 21)
    - Fairchild Inc. (Box 21)
    - Fairlane Gear, Inc. (Box 21)
    - Fantasee Lighting (Box 21)
    - Fibercote Industries, Inc., 1998 (Box 21)
    - Fiberrite, 1996 (Box 21)
    - Findlay Industries (Box 21)
    - First Inertia Switch, 1996 (Box 21)
    - Flotec, 1998 (Box 21)
    - Ford Motor Company, 1997 (Box 21)
    - Form Tech., 1998-1999 (Box 21)
    - Fox Racing Shox, 1999-2002 (Box 21)
    - GE Pistons, 1998-1999 (Box 21)
    - General Motors Corporation, 2003-2005 (Box 21)
    - GH Craft, Ltd., 1996 (Box 21)
    - Gochermann Solar Technologies, 2000 (Box 21)
    - Goldenwest, Mfg., Inc. (Box 21)
    - GTE (Box 21)
    - Guardian Industries, 1993 (Box 21)
    - Haldex Barnes Corporation, 1989 (Box 21)
    - Handy & Harman (Box 21)
    - Helical Flexible Couplings (Box 21)
    - Helios Technology, 1991 (Box 21)
    - Hercules Inc., 1991 (Box 21)
    - Hewlett Packard (Box 21)
    - Hexel, 1998-2000 (Box 21)
    - Hi-Lex, 2001 (Box 21)
    - Hi-Tech Hose (Box 21)
    - Hiltronics, Inc. (Box 21)
    - Huelsberg Custom, 1997 (Box 21)
    - International Business Machines -- IBM (Box 21)
    - ICI Fiberrite, 1994 (Box 21)
    - IE&E, 2001 (Box 21)
    - Infortrieve Indexing (Box 21)
    - Jackie's Transport (Box 21)
    - John Brad Tool Co., 1999 (Box 21)
    - Johnson Lumber, 1997 (Box 21)
    - Kavaco Company, 1994 (Box 21)
    - KBK Subway, Inc. (Box 21)
    - Keirn Motor Company (Box 21)
    - Keithley Instruments, 1998-1999 (Box 21)
    - Kenna Metal, 1998-1999 (Box 21)
    - Kohler, 1997-1998 (Box 21)
    - KonneKtech, 1994 (Box 21)
    - Kyocera America, Inc., 1991 (Box 21)
    - La-Man Corporation Filters Division, 1998 (Box 21)
    - Lemo, 2000 (Box 21)
    - Lexington Company, 1998 (Box 21)
    - Lewcott Corporation (Box 21)
    - LG Chem (Box 21)
    - Littol Fuse, 1999 (Box 21)
    - Loclite, 2000 (Box 21)
    - Mack Industries, 1999-2000 (Box 21)
    - Mac Steel (Box 21)
    - Magna-Atoma, 1998 (Box 21)
    - Masco Industries, 1993 (Box 21)
    - MascoTech (Box 21)
    - Matarah Industries, 1997-1998 (Box 22)
    - Matlab (Box 22)
    - Metalmite (Box 22)
    - Michigan International Speedway, 1994 (Box 22)
    - Micro-Air (Slade Associate), 1997 (Box 22)
    - Micronel, 1998 (Box 22)
    - Microsoft (Box 22)
    - Mitsubishi Electric (Box 22)
    - Monroe Auto Equipment (Box 22)
    - Morse Controls (Box 22)
    - Motorala HQ (Box 22)
    - Mr. Trivedi (Box 22)
    - National Industrial Automation (Box 22)
    - National Instruments (Box 22)
    - Newark Electronics (Box 22)
    - Noble Corporation (Box 22)
    - Noleen, 1993 (Box 22)
    - Norton Diamond Film (Box 22)
    - Nowatzke Great Dane/GMC Truck (Box 22)
    - NRG (Box 22)
    - NSK Corporation, 1993 (Box 22)
    - NTN (Box 22)
    - Nukem, 1991-1993 (Box 22)
    - Office of the Vice President for Research (Box 22)
    - Office of the Vice President of Student Affairs (Box 22)
    - Offshore Spar Lo. (Box 22)
    - OHAUS (Box 22)
    - Omega (Box 22)
    - Osburn Trucking, 2000 (Box 22)
    - Packard-Delphi (Box 22)
    - Panasonic HQ, 1997-1998 (Box 22)
    - Penske, 2001 (Box 22)
    - Pepsi (Box 22)
    - PES International, 1994 (Box 22)
    - Photocomm International (Box 22)
    - Physical Acoustics Corporation, 1994 (Box 22)
    - Pinnacle Express (Box 22)
    - Presidents Tuxedo (Box 22)
    - Preventative Care (Box 22)
    - Proctor and Gamble, 1998 (Box 22)
    - Project Management Associates Inc. (Box 22)
    - Protel Technology (Box 22)
    - Pura, Inc., 1997 (Box 22)
    - Purchase Radio Supply (Box 22)
    - Rare Earth Coatings, 1999 (Box 22)
    - Raspberry Hill Publishing, Inc., 1998 (Box 22)
    - Raychen (Box 22)
    - RDC (Box 22)
    - Resin Services, Inc., 1994 (Box 22)
    - Ring Technologies (Box 22)
    - RMI (Box 22)
    - Rudolph Brothers (Box 22)
    - S-3 Engineering, 2000 (Box 22)
    - SAE (Box 22)
    - Safety Services, 1997-1998 (Box 22)
    - Sanyo (Box 22)
    - Scaled Composites (Box 22)
    - Select Machinery, Inc., 1998 (Box 22)
    - Senator Joe Young, 1997 (Box 22)
    - Skip Barber Racing School, 1999 (Box 22)
    - Solarex (Box 22)
    - Solec International, 1991 (Box 22)
    - Spartech Plastics, 1994 (Box 22)
    - Spectrodata, 2000 (Box 22)
    - SPS Technologies, 2000 (Box 22)
    - Square D (Box 22)
    - SST (Box 22)
    - Stadco Advanced Tooling (Box 22)
    - Stanley Vidmar (Box 22)
    - Staples (Box 22)
    - Starmet Corporation (Box 22)
    - Sun Standard, Inc. (Box 22)
    - Tap Magic Corporation (Box 22)
    - Teclab (Box 22)
    - TecStar (Box 22)
    - Tektronix (Box 22)
    - Telulex, Inc. (Box 22)
    - Terminal Supply (Box 22)
    - Thermoid (Box 22)
    - Tico Titanium, Inc. (Box 22)
    - Trailer Technologies (Box 22)
    - Trutron, 2005 (Box 22)
    - TRW (Box 22)
    - Ulrich's (Box 22)
    - UMAC of Tuscon, AZ (Box 22)
    - United Industrial Equipment Corp. (Box 22)
    - University of Michigan Credit Union, 1999 (Box 22)
    - University Lithoprinters (Box 22)
    - UTA (Box 22)
    - Vehicle Research and Development, Inc. (Box 22)
    - Vehma International (Box 22)
    - Vicor, 1999-2003 (Box 22)
    - Wahl Instruments Inc. (Box 22)
    - Wahoo Composites, 2000 (Box 22)
    - Wavecrest Laboratories (Box 22)
    - W.H. Brady (Box 22)
    - Wheelsmith Fabrications, Inc., 1992 (Box 22)
    - Wie, 1999 (Box 22)
    - Wilton Corporation (Box 22)
    - Workplace Integrators, 2000 (Box 22)
    - WSI Corporation, 1993 (Box 22)
    - Xerox (Box 22)
    - Xilinx (Box 22)
    - Yardley Technical Products, 1990 (Box 22)
    - Yasakawa Electric (Box 22)
    - Yokogawa (Box 22)
    - Zoltek, 1998 (Box 22)
  - Student Papers (Box 23)
    - Aerodynamics Design of an Ultra-Streamlined Solar Electric Vehicle, 1999 (Box 23)
      [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2078 ]
    - M-Pulse Design and Implementation, 2000 (Box 23)
    - M-Pulse Team Reports, 2001 (Box 23)
    - MaizeBlaze Team Reports, 1998-1999 (Box 23)
    - Solar Car Team, 1990-1993 (Box 23)
    - Spectrum Team Reports, 2003 (Box 23)
    - Sunrayce '93 Weather Forecasting Report, 1993 (Box 23)
    - Wolverine Team Reports, 1997 (Box 23)
- Website
  The Website series consists of two website captures July 23, 2000 (2,193 digital records, 52.1 MB) and April 24, 2009, (91,911 digital files, 708 digital folders).
  The July 23, 2000 website capture, transferred via File Transfer Protocol, is comprised of the entire contents of the Solar Car Team website as they appeared on the transfer date. The website includes HTML files, image files, PDF files of newsletters, and four RealAudio files. The original organization and structure of the online files has been preserved in the archived website. Content of links external to the University of Michigan has not been included in the website subseries, though a citation to the original Universal Resource Locator (URL) can be found within the content of the digital records.
  The website includes information for public dissemination on Solar Car teams, sponsors, and races. Six of the Solar Car Teams are represented in the website: Sunrunner, Maize & Blue, Solar Vision, Wolverine, MaizeBlaze, and MPulse. Though documentation is available in varying degrees for each team, most team pages include information on the team members, the technical specifications for that team's car, team sponsors, and an extensive collection of photographs of races and events in which the team participated. Of particular interest are the pages for the MaizeBlaze team, which include audio and journal accounts from race team members for the team's entry in the World Solar Challenge.
  The website also includes year-by-year information on the Solar Car Team's participation in two major races, the GM Sunrayce and the World Solar Challenge, information for visitors about building solar cars and sponsoring the team, and issues of the team's monthly newsletter. A large number of thumbnail and full-size digitized photographs and digital images, mainly of team members and team activities, are also included.
  The Website 2006-2009 subseries features a snapshot of the Solar Car Team's website (http://solarcar.engin.umich.edu/). The website snapshot was harvested by the University Archives staff in April 2009 using the software HTTrack website copier downloaded from: http://www.httrack.com/. The website includes information on the current solar car Infinium (2009). The website is divided into news, sponsors, recruitment information, about us, donation information, and multimedia sections. Information regarding past teams and cars is small. The multimedia section features photographs from 2006 to present of the team, races, and cars. The website is in Drupal; an open source software package freely available for publishing, managing, and organizing a website (http://drupal.org). Blogs are heavily used on the website and the different sections are posted to in a blog format, chronologically from the top down.
  - Website (as of July 23, 2000), 1 optical disks CD-ROMs (Box 1)
  - Website Capture (as of April 24, 2009), 2 optical disks CD-ROMs (Box 5)
  - Solar Car team Blog Capture (as of July 22, 2008) (Box 5)
  - Solar Car Website Capture, July 2010-ongoing
  - 3_D Super Ultimate Solar Car Racing Website Capture, July 2010-ongoing